<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on gzt does statistics</title>
    <link>http://gzt.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on gzt does statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gzt.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrixdist News</title>
      <link>http://gzt.github.io/post/matrixdist-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gzt.github.io/post/matrixdist-new/</guid>
      <description>I have just finished setting up handling for AR(1) and compound symmetry variance structures in my maximum likelihood estimation function for matrix variate normal distributions in matrixdist. This means I may submit it to CRAN soon (it’s currently available on github). An example:
library(matrixdist) A &amp;lt;- rmatrixnorm(100, mean=array(0,dim=c(3,4)), U = toeplitz(c(1,.8,.64)), V = rWishart(1,7,diag(4))[,,1]) mle.matrixnorm(A, row.variance=&amp;quot;AR(1)&amp;quot;) $mean [,1] [,2] [,3] [,4] [1,] -0.23319124 0.101052880 0.2857941 0.2972354 [2,] -0.10564149 0.002280582 0.1703971 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with C and R</title>
      <link>http://gzt.github.io/post/working-with-c-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gzt.github.io/post/working-with-c-and-r/</guid>
      <description>or: adventures with .Call Generally I work either in R or in C but not both. My research is trying to do some big things faster and there’s existing code in C that I’m working with. I might dump some output and then explore it in R, but I don’t need to interface between them. On the other hand, when consulting with others it’s going to come down to good old-fashioned statistics so that happens in R (or SAS if applicable, for some things it’s better and for some things the people you’re working with are using SAS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why I&#39;ve been using base plot</title>
      <link>http://gzt.github.io/post/why-i-ve-been-using-base-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gzt.github.io/post/why-i-ve-been-using-base-plot/</guid>
      <description>Nobody cares what I think, of course. The grammar of graphics is The Way, and ggplot2 is my preferred method of visualization. I never even really tried to make my own graphs with base plot until some point last fall (so: after 5 years of R) - I mean, I’m at Iowa State, after all. I don’t hang out with our Graphics Group as much as I should but that’s how I think about plotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some linear algebra tricks</title>
      <link>http://gzt.github.io/post/some-linear-algebra-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gzt.github.io/post/some-linear-algebra-tricks/</guid>
      <description>You may have come across some of this before, but I wanted to write this down for some future reference because it came up in a project of mine and I want to refer to it later. The general theme is that if you know something about the structure of the matrices you’re working with, you can sometimes speed some things up.
Avoiding matrix inversion. Why do you want to invert your matrix?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>