<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C on gzt does statistics</title>
    <link>/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C on gzt does statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Version of CholWishart Released</title>
      <link>/2019/01/08/new-version-of-cholwishart-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/08/new-version-of-cholwishart-released/</guid>
      <description>I have just released version 0.9.4 of CholWishart. If you want to simulate from the inverse Wishart, compute densities for the Wishart or inverse Wishart, or use the multivariate gamma or digamma function, this is the R package for you. It has a few other functions (notably, its namesake which generates random samples from the Wishart distribution and returns their Cholesky decomposition).
New in this release: the pseudo Wishart and its pseudo-inverse, the generalized inverse Wishart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with C and R</title>
      <link>/2018/02/13/working-with-c-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/13/working-with-c-and-r/</guid>
      <description>or: adventures with .Call Generally I work either in R or in C but not both. My research is trying to do some big things faster and there’s existing code in C that I’m working with. I might dump some output and then explore it in R, but I don’t need to interface between them. On the other hand, when consulting with others it’s going to come down to good old-fashioned statistics so that happens in R (or SAS if applicable, for some things it’s better and for some things the people you’re working with are using SAS).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>