<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on gzt does statistics</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on gzt does statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper announcement: matching fragments using images of fracture surface replicas</title>
      <link>/2022/05/01/new-paper-announcement-matching-fragments-using-images-of-fracture-surface-replicas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/05/01/new-paper-announcement-matching-fragments-using-images-of-fracture-surface-replicas/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce a new paper in the Journal of Forensic Sciences, Quantitative matching of forensic evidence fragments utilizing 3D microscopy analysis of fracture surface replicas, which extends our prior work on fracture matching. Here we show that the method works when, instead of matching two fracture surfaces directly, we instead use replicas, which is common in forensic applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know your PRNGs</title>
      <link>/2019/03/09/know-your-prngs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/09/know-your-prngs/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR version: if all you&amp;rsquo;re using the standalone R math library in C for is generating uniform random numbers, I have a little C program to remove that dependency as long as you don&amp;rsquo;t mind your seeds not having the same output as R. I might even fix that later.
I fell into a rabbit hole recently - I do a fair amount of work in C using the R standalone math library for pseudo-random number generation (PRNGs) and sometimes some of its special functions (rather than, say, working in C so it will be called from R or trying to implement a PRNG myself or a special function myself - leave RNGs and numerical analysis to experts).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>